The Parker Bailey Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Parker Bailey Papers
1899-1977
MSS 34
Yale University Music Library
2.9
(7 boxes)
Music, correspondence and other writings, photographs, and additional materials by and about the American composer, pianist, and lawyer Parker Bailey (1902-1982).
Bailey, Parker, 1902-1982
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Parker Bailey Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Bailey in 1980.
Arrangement
In 10 series as follows: I. Personal correspondence. II. Business correspondence. III. Contracts, royalty statements, and certificates. IV. Literary writings. V. Miscellaneous jottings and papers. VI. Programs. VII. Newspaper clippings. VIII. Miscellaneous bulletins, reports, and brochures. IX. Photographs and pictures. X. Musical works.
Scope and Contents
The Parker Bailey Papers contain sketches, manuscript scores, and published editions of Bailey's musical compositions, including keyboard pieces, chamber music, songs, and choral works. Bailey's life and work are also documented by: correspondence; literary writings; programs; newspaper clippings; photographs; and miscellaneous items.
Biographical / Historical
The composer, pianist, and lawyer Parker Bailey was born in Kansas City, Missouri, on March 1, 1902. His early years were spent in Telluride, Colorado, Salt Lake City, and San Francisco.
In 1919 Bailey came to Yale to study composition with his uncle Horatio Parker, the Dean of the Yale School of Music, but Parker died that same year. Bailey studied instead with David Stanley Smith, receiving the B.A. in 1923. He continued his education at the Cleveland Institute of Music, where he studied with Quincy Porter and Roger Sessions.
In 1931 Bailey entered Cornell Law School, but during summer vacations he continued to devote himself to music. Friendships with organists led him to write frequently for the organ. He composed the Variations Symphoniques for organ for Arthur Quimby, who performed it at the Cleveland Museum of Art in 1930. (It was not published until 1937.) Toccata-Ricercata-Finale for organ was written for Edward Arthur Kraft and first performed by him in 1933 in Cleveland. The H.W. Gray Company published it in 1958. Bailey's arrangement of his Toccata-Ricercata-Finale for two pianos was first performed in New Haven in 1935 or 1936 by Bruce and Rosalind Simonds.
After receiving the LL.B. degree from Cornell in 1934, Bailey found a job with the Joseph Robinson Truesdale Firm in New York. In 1937 he moved to the New York Law Revision Commission. Two years later, he joined the legal staff of the Securities and Exchange Commission in Washington, D.C.
Bailey's growing legal responsibilities did not prevent him from remaining active in music. He later wrote, "The 2-piano texture has always interested me, and in Cleveland I occasionally operated one piano with Arthur Loesser at the other. When I started work in the General Counsel's office of the S.E.C. in Washington in the fall of 1939, I was for the first extended stretch in my career equipped not with one but with no piano." Despite the problems created by the absence of the "88-note device," Bailey composed nonetheless. "The evolving piece was a prelude and fugue on the chorale 'Wachet Auf,'" Bailey explained. "I thought of the fugue subject on a railroad coach rolling from Washington to Brooklyn late in 1939. By that time I had found out that my general overlord, Chester T. Lane, who was General Counsel of the S.E.C., was an avid reader of two-piano music. By the summer of 1940 Beryl Rubinstein and Arthur Loesser were practicing [the prelude and fugue] in Cleveland, and in October they included it in their Town Hall recital in New York."
Bailey remained with the SEC in Washington until 1942, at which time he returned to New York and began work with Davis, Polk, & Wardwell Attorneys. His association with this firm continued to his retirement in 1971. He died in 1982.
Composers -- Correspondence; Lawyers -- Correspondence; Music -- United States -- 20th Century; Organ music; Piano music; Songs; Bailey, Parker, 1902-1982; Baron, Samuel, 1925-1997; Bauer, Marion, 1882-1955; Baumgartner, H. Leroy (Hope Leroy), 1891-1969; Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990; Downes, Olin, 1886-1955; Keene, Christopher; Kirkpatrick, John, 1905-1991; Kolodin, Irving, 1908-1988; Noss, Luther, 1907-1995; Piety, Chauncey R. (Chauncey Roscoe); Rubinstein, Beryl, 1898-1952; Shepherd, Arthur, 1880-1958; Simonds, Bruce; Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1894-1995; Stojowski, Sigismund, 1870-1946; Society for the Publication of American Music
- Personal Correspondence, Series I
  General
  Arranged alphabetically by the name of the correspondent. Because the Parker Bailey correspondence includes many copies of his own letters, correspondence from and to him has been organized together to keep the chronology. Letters are to Bailey unless otherwise stated. Bailey's own letters can be assumed to be carbons unless there is a note to the contrary.
  - General, I.A
    - Alexander, Hugh, 1932 Aug 10; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
      1 typed letter from Parker Bailey
      See also: Contracts (III)
    - Arent, Albert E., 1973 Dec 27; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
      1 typed letter signed
    - Aubin, [Walivara?], no year May 15; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
      1 autograph letter signed
    - Bagger, Louis and Patty, [1975 Jan]; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
      1 card signed
      1 typed letter signed from Parker Bailey
      See also: Newspaper Articles and Programs (VI, VII)
    - Bailey, Raymond, [1955 May 11]; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bailey, Mrs. Stephen A., [1940 Oct 26]; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
      1 autograph letter signed from Parker Bailey
      See also: Newspaper Articles concerning works by Parker Bailey (VII.A)-- "Duo pianists..." 10-26-40; letter from Robert M. Blair-Smith
    - Baron, Samuel, 1975 July; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
      2 typed letters signed from Parker Bailey (1 original)
    - Bauer, Marion, 1940 Feb 16; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
      1 autograph letter signed from Parker Bailey (original)
    - Baumgartner, H.L., 1963 Jan; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
      1 typed postcard signed
    - Bernstein, [Leonard], [1963?]; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Blair-Smith, Robert M., 1942 May 24; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
      2 typed letters signed to Mrs. Stephen A. Bailey
    - Buffin, Robert J., 1975 Jun 18; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Burdick, Charles K., 1937 Dec 2; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Burr, George L., 1934-1937; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
      2 autograph letters signed
    - Cantrell, Burton, 1970 Dec 2; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Carnes, Duane J., no date; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 1)
      See also: Programs (VI)--The Music Maker's Program, 11-18-46.
    - Clarke, Gilmore D., 1973-1974; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Downes, Olin, 1935-1938; 5 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
      2 typed letters from Parker Bailey (copies)
      2 typed letters signed
      1 typed letter signed from Downes' secretary
      See also: Newspaper Clippings -- Letters to the Editor (VII.C).
    - Farnham, William H., 1937 Dec 1; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Faulkner, Barry, 1960 Jul 27; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Fisher, Meloy, 1975 Aug; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
      1 typed letter from Parker Bailey (no salutation)
      1 typed letter signed from Parker Bailey to Mary Ashe (San Francisco Public Library) attached
    - Freeman, Frank, [1958?]-1970; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
      See also: Poetry by Parker Bailey (IV.A.1)--"Sublimated sterility."
    - The Great Awards Collection, 1975 Jan 16; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Henshaw, Paul C. (Homestake Mining Company), 1971; 4 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
      2 typed letters signed from Parker Bailey
    - Keene, Christopher (Metropolitan Opera), 1972; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Kirkpatrick, John, 1974; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
      1 autograph letter signed (on back of article sent)
    - Kolodin, Irving, 1969 Jun 23; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 2)
      See also: Miscellaneous Newspaper Articles (VII.F).
    - Kraft, Edwin Arthur and Marie, 1941-1958; 7 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
      3 autograph letters signed from Edwin Archur Kraft, 2 with attached musical notes
      1 autograph postcard signed from Edwin Arthur Kraft
      1 autograph letter signed from Marie
      1 typed letter with attached questions from Parker Bailey
      1 separate sheet of questions
    - Leach, Barry, 1958 Nov 10; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Lerew, Donna and Stoesser, Marie, 1971 Nov 18; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Liggett, Carr, 1943-1962; 4 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Metropolitan Opera House (Box 1, Folder 2)
      See: Christopher Keene.
    - Noss, Luther, 1939 Apr 21; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Piety, Chauncey Roscoe, 1927-1973; 33 items (Box 1, Folder 3)
      24 typed letters signed
      1 typed letter signed to Arthur Shepherd
      1 typed letter signed from Rodeheater Co. to Chauncey Roscoe Piety, attached to letter to Parker Bailey
      1 typed letter signed from Parker Bailey to H.O. Piety (son of Chauncey Roscoe Piety)
      1 biography of CRP
      2 church programs
      2 leaflets
      See also: Library.,of,-.Congress letters (II.A) and Poetry by Piety (IV.A.2)
    - Rubinstein, Beryl, 1940; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Semler, G. Herbert Jr. and Evelyn, 1938-1976; 11 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
      1 typed note signed with attached article
      4 typed letters signed from Parker Bailey (2 originals)
      1 autograph note signed
      1 flyer
      1 note on envelope [from?]
      1 photocopy of page from OED 1933
    - Shepherd, Arthur, 1935-1952; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
      See also: C.R. Piety letters
    - Sherman, Robert (WQXR), 1974-1975; 4 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
      3 typed letters signed from Parker Bailey
    - Simonds, Bruce, 1963; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Stojowski, Sigismond, 1939 Nov; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
      See also: Library of Congress letters (II.A)
    - Streeter, Ed, 1972 Jan 8; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Titus, Parvin, 1937 Aug 20; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 4)
      See also: Programs (VI)
    - WQXR (Box 1, Folder 4)
      See: Robert Sherman
    - White, Peregrine, 1963 Aug 7; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Whittemore, Arthur and Lowe, Jack, 1947 Feb 16; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Christmas Cards, I.B
    - Buchman, Carl, [1974-1975]; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 5)
      2 cards
    - Dimmler, Charlie and Edie, no date; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 5)
      1 card
    - Green, Clark and Dick, no date; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Shiplacaff, Fred and Marguerite, [1977 Dec]; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Swatek, Paul and Kitty, [1977 Dec]; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified (only first names, initials or titles), I.C
    - B, 1973 Jul 11; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - HC, no date; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 6)
      1 memo from Parker Bailey (unsigned)
      1 draft of letter to Mrs. Walter Hinrichsen from Parker Bailey
    - Charlotte, 1960 Feb 13; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Dean, 1934 Jul 2; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - OG, 1972 Feb; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - mej (Orchestra of America), 1961 Feb 23; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jane and Barclay, 1936 Sept 17; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 6)
      1 telegram
      1 photocopy of above
    - The Maj, 1964 Feb 22; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - EM, 1971 Nov; 4 items (Box 1, Folder 6)
      1 typed letter signed on receiver copy of one of above
    - Otto, 1968 Mar 3; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 6)
      2 typed letters signed from Parker Bailey (copies)
    - ES, 1975 Jun 2; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 6)
      1 typed letter signed from Parker Bailey (original)
      1 carbon copy of above
      See also: Program --Works by Parker Bailey (VI.A) for Trinity Cathedral Church 50th Anniversary (E.A. Kraft biography)
    - hbt, no date; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 6)
      1 typed card signed
    - --Possibly intended for G.H. Semler, 1975 Apr 13; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 6)
      1 partial photocopy of flute part from Parker Bailey's Sonata for Flute and Piano, 2 p. See also: Music--Parker Bailey's Instrumental Works (X.A.1)
      1 score of Summer is Singing; 4 p. See also: Music--Parker Bailey's Choral Works (X.A.3)
- Business Correspondence, Series II
  Arranged alphabetically by the name of the individual or institution. In cases where a person or company is part of another company (such as Belwin Mills and H.W. Gray Companies) their correspondence has been combined and cross-references have been made. Enclosures have been kept with letters in as many cases as possible, except for Contracts, Royalty Statements, and Certificates.
  - Related to Music, II.A
    - À la Flûte de Pan, 1937; 13 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
      1 catalogue
      4 typed letters signed
      2 autograph letters from Parker Bailey (rough drafts)
      3 receipts
    - Adams, Horst (Box 1, Folder 7)
      See: Slonimsky, Nicolas
    - Associated Music Publishers, Inc., 1944 Apr 3; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Belwin Mills Publishing Company (Box 1, Folder 7)
      See: H.W. Gray Company
    - Bodleian Library, Oxford, 1939 Jul 26; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Burge and Company, Ltd., no date; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
      2 form letters (ads)
    - C.F. Peters (Mr. and Mrs. Walter Hinrichsen), 1962-1975; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
      1 autograph letter signed to Arnold Broido (copy) with note to Parker Bailey
      4 typed letters signed from Parker Bailey
      1 copy each of two of above
      1 rough draft by Parker Bailey with note dated 1-27-75
      1 rough draft by Parker Bailey with attached quote
    - California State University (Arnold T. Schwab), 1972; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Carl Fischer, Inc., 1937-1948; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
      See also: S.P.A.M.
    - Cleveland Institute of Music, 1975; 5 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
      2 rough drafts of above
    - Cleveland Public Library, 1975; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Columbia University, 1975; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Cornell University, 1966-1975; 14 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
      6 typed letters signed
      2 copies of 1 typed letter
      4 typed letters from Parker Bailey
      1 receipt
      1 brochure (Includes: Lucien Tharaud, Utah Power and Light Co., Morgan Guaranty Trust, Alfred Sapersteen, Robert Haley, J.M. Bailey, etc.)
    - D. Appleton-Century Company, Inc., 1935 Aug 17; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - D.C. Heath and Company, 1935 Dec 31; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Eastman School of Music, 1975; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Editions Maurice Senart, 1936; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 8)
      2 typed letters from Parker Bailey
    - Edward Brothers, 1975; 26 items (Box 1, Folder 8)
      4 typed letters signed (Joyce Bekker, Sales Coordinator)
      10 typed letters signed from Parker Bailey
      2 estimates for printing
      1 typed note from Parker Bailey
      1 acknowledgment
      1 statement
      2 bills of lading
      2 score samples
      1 memo from Parker Bailey
      1 invoice
    - The Edwin A. Fleischer Music Collection (The Free Library of Philadelphia), 1958 Oct 1-4; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - G. Schirmer (Box 1, Folder 8)
      See: S.P.A.M.
    - H.W. Gray and Co./Belwin Mills Publishing Corporation, 1936-1972; 22 items (Box 1, Folder 9)
      12 typed letters signed
      3 typed letters from Parker Bailey
      1 statement of sales
      1 bill
      1 announcement of composition competition
      1 memo
      1 autograph note from Parker Bailey
      See also: Programs (VI)--7-15-58 letter from George Krumm attached to Trinity Cathedral 50th anniversary program
    - Harvard University Press, 1937-1941; 4 items (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Hearst Magazine Company, Inc., 1938; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 9)
      1 note attached to above
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1939; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Joseph Boonin, Inc., 1972 Oct 3; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Library of Congress, 1937-1975; 23 items (Box 1, Folder 9)
      10 typed letters signed to Edward N. Waters (2 originals)
      1 essay by Parker Bailey on his sonata for flute and piano
      3 typed letters signed from Edward Waters
      1 form
    - The Edward MacDowell Association, Inc., 1955-1960; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 9)
      5 typed letters signed
      1 list
      1 draft of form letter
    - National Orchestral Association, 1972-1973; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 10)
      3 financial statements
    - New York Public Library, 1975; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 10)
      1 acknowledgement
    - Newark Public Library, 1975; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 10)
      1 autograph letter signed from G. Semler to William Dane (3 typed copies, 1 unsigned)
      1 rough draft of above
    - Oliver Ditson/Theodore Presser Co., 1930-1975; 33 items (Box 1, Folder 10)
      15 typed letters signed
      3 typed letters from Parker Bailey (1 incomplete)
      1 announcement
      1 rough draft by Parker Bailey
      1 sample outline
      1 sample letter
      1 press release
    - The Orchestra of America, Inc. (William J. Kridel), 1971 June 10; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 10)
      1 typed letter
      1 notice
      1 plan of dissolution
      See also: Miscellaneous Bulletins, Reports and Brochures (VIII)
    - Oxford University Press, 1935-1962; 12 items (Box 1, Folder 10)
      1 credit ticket
    - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1971-1975; 11 items (Box 1, Folder 11)
      7 typed letters signed
      1 typed letter from Parker Bailey with attached note
    - San Francisco Public Library (Mary Ashe) (Box 1, Folder 11)
      See: Personal Correspondence, General (I.A)--letter to Meloy Fisher from Parker Bailey
    - Silver Burdett and Company, 1935-1936; 6 items (Box 1, Folder 11)
      2 additional typed letters signed
      2 receipts
    - Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1955-1970; 17 items (Box 1, Folder 11)
      3 additional typed letters signed
      2 typed letters from Parker Bailey (1 photocopy)
      5 typed letters signed from Parker Bailey (1 photocopy with excerpt from Nicolas Slonimsky letter)
      3 copies of 3 of above typed letters signed
      1 excerpt of letter to Parker Bailey (from Nicolas Slonimsky)
      1 incomplete typed letter from Parker Bailey [original?]
      (Includes: correspondence with Riemann Musiklexicon)
      See also: Programs (VI)--"Musical Fantasies perpetrated as Fact"
    - Society for the Publication of American Music (S.P.A.M.), 1928-1975; 106 items (Box 1, Folder 12)
      21 typed letters signed
      5 autograph letters signed (Includes: letters from Philip James [President of S.P.A.M.], Nathan Broder of G. Schirmer, Inc., William Burnet Tuthill [Secretary of S.P.A.M.], Oscar Wagner [Secretary of S.P.A.M.], Burnet Corwin Tuthill [Treasurer of S.P.A.M.] and Edward Ballantine, composer)
      19 typed letters signed from Parker Bailey (18 originals)
      13 typed letters from Parker Bailey (4 originals)
      1 typed card signed from Parker Bailey
      1 autograph card signed from Parker Bailey
      (Includes: letters from B.C. Tuthill, N. Broder, P. James, Eric von der Goltz, W.B. Tuthill, O. Wagner and E. Ballantine)
      12 typed letters signed to and from others (1 carbon, 1 photocopy)
      9 typed letters to and from others (4 copies, 5 photocopies from Folder 1/13)
      2 drafts to and from others
      1 autograph card signed to and from others
      (Includes: letters to and from P. James, N. Broder, B.C. Tuthill and A. Walter Kramer (President of S.P.A.M.))
      3 lists of publications
      1 blank sheet of S.P.A.M. stationary
      1 page of budget figures (photocopy from Folder 1/13)
      1 proof
      2 biographical sketches
      1 check
      1 inventory list
      1 list of music plates, etc.
      1 report on S.P.A.M. gross receits (photocopy from Folder 1/13)
      1 proxy statement
      2 copies of notice to S.P.A.M. composers
      1 copy of poem by Parker Bailey
      1 list of compositions by B.C. Tuthill
      2 copies of memo
    - Theodore Presser Company (Arnold Broido) (Box 1, Folder 12)
      See: Oliver Ditson Company
    - University of North Carolina, 1975; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 12)
      1 biography
    - Westmore Music Corporation, 1942; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Yale University, 1945-1971; 11 items (Box 1, Folder 12)
      3 typed letters signed (1 photocopy)
      6 postcards
      1 Yale newsletter
    - Disintegrating letters, 12 items (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Originals of items in S.P.A.M. file (10) plus 1 each from Contracts (III) and Poetry by Parker Bailey (IV.A.1)
  - Not Related to Music, II.B
    - Davis, Polk and Wardwell, 1971-1972; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 14)
      3 memorandum (photocopies)
    - Department of State (Division of Licenses), 1937-1938; 7 items (Box 1, Folder 14)
      2 notices
      1 notification of appointment as Notary Public
    - First National Bank of Nevada, 1974 Aug 5; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Goodbody and Company (Box 1, Folder 14)
      See: Ohio Citizens Trust Company
    - Guaranty Trust Company of New York (Box 1, Folder 14)
      See: Trinity Cathedral
    - Homestake Mining Company (Box 1, Folder 14)
      See: Personal Correspondence, General (I.A)--Paul Henshaw
    - MacDonald, John W., 1937 Dec 13; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Monroe Auto Equipment Stock Co., no date; 5 items (Box 1, Folder 14)
      3 notices with 2 proxies
      2 form letters to stockholders
    - Morgan Guaranty Trust Company (Box 1, Folder 14)
      See: Business Correspondence related to Music (II.A)-Cornell University
    - Ohio Citizens Trust Company, 1962; 15 items (Box 1, Folder 14)
      6 statements
      1 pamphlet
      1 form letter
    - Smith, Barney and Company (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Telluride Association, 1960-1961; 3 items (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Timken Roller Bearing Company (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Trinity Cathedral, 1954-1958; 21 items (Box 1, Folder 14)
      7 typed letters signed (1 copy)
      6 typed letters from Parker Bailey
      2 form letters
      1 delivery bill
      1 IBM card with printed notice attached
    - Walker Bank and Trust Company, 1960 Aug 23; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Unindentified, II.C
    - LCM, 1962 Apr 14; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 14)
      1 typed letter (carbon)
- Contracts, Royalty Statements and Certificates, Series III
  Arranged by the name of individual or institution
  - Alexander, Hugh, 1928 Dec 24; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 1)
    2 copies of 1 contract
  - C.C. Birchard and Company, 1930 Feb 18; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 1)
    1 contract
  - Carl Fischer, Inc., 1935 Apr 16; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - G. Schirmer (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hitchens, Jennie D., 1934 Oct 17; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Library of Congress, 1929-1941; 5 items (Box 2, Folder 1)
    3 certificates
    1 circular
    1 acknowledgement with typed
    note attached
  - Oliver Ditson/Theodore Presser Company, 1928-1975; 22 items (Box 2, Folder 1)
    9 contracts
    12 royalty statements
    1 check stub
  - Society for the Publication of American Music (S.P.A.M.), 1929-1950; 9 items (Box 2, Folder 1)
    2 contracts between S.P.A.M. and Parker Bailey
    1 copy of 1 of above
    4 contracts between S.P.A.M. and G. Schirmer (1 photocopy from Folder 12, Box 1)
- Literary Writings, Series IV
  - Poetry, IV.A
    - Poetry by Parker Bailey, IV.A.1
      - Anaticulam Amamus, no date; 3 items (Box 2, Folder 2)
        3 typed copies (2 photocopies)
      - Sublimated Sterility, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
        1 typed copy
      - The Unanswered Question, no date; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
        1 autograph copy
      - Untitled, 1964 Dec 22; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)